Finding Aid for Matthew Neumeier papers, 1977-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Matthew Neumeier papers 1977-1990 1978-1981 and 1988-1990
Neumeier, Matthew
2 linear feet
861113 Aa 2
Student at the University of Michigan. Papers relating to his interest in the administration of the University Cellar bookstore, and relating to the renovation of the Michigan Union.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were donated by Mr. Neumeier in two accessions 1981 and March, 1991 (donor no. 6649 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Matthew Neumeier is from Escanaba Michigan. He attended the University of Michigan during the 1972/1973 academic year and again from 1979 to 1981, graduating in 1981. He served on the Board of Directors of the University Cellar bookstore from 1979 to 1981. He was also active in the renovation of the Michigan Union from 1980 to 1981. After graduating he attended Harvard Law School. While practicing law in Ann Arbor, he became an alumni representative to the Michigan Union Board of Representatives serving two terms beginning in April of 1988.
The Neumeier collection has two series, one relating to the administration of the University Cellar bookstore, the other concerning the renovation of the Michigan Union and his involvement with the Michigan Union Board of Representatives. This later series includes an incomplete run of minutes and reports from February 1988 to September 1990.
Subjects:
University Cellar.; Michigan Union.
- University Cellar, Board of Directors
  - Dated files, undated and 1978-July 1981, 37 folders (Box 1)
  - Labor negotiations, 1979, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Expansion Committee report, April 1979 (Box 1)
  - Articles of incorporation, by-laws, unified policies, January 1977 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
- Michigan Union
  - Renovation of the Michigan Union
    - March 1980-May 1981, 8 folders (Box 2)
    - Michigan Union marketing study, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Union Board of Representatives
    - Charter, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Marketing/Space Committees (Box 2)
    - Michigan Union/North Campus Commons Organizational Assessment, July 1989 (Box 2)
    - Minutes
      - February 1988 (Box 2)
      - September-December 1988 (Box 2)
      - January-February 1989 (Box 2)
      - March-April 1989 (Box 2)
      - June-December 1989 (Box 2)
      - January-June 1990 (Box 2)
      - September 1990 (Box 2)
    - Policies (Box 2)
    - Report of the Task Force to Study the Future of the Michigan Union, October 1979 (Box 2)
    - Rosters, 1988-1990 (Box 2)